ou.edu 2011-06-05

# Privacy Policy - Public Affairs - The University of Oklahoma

The University of Oklahoma is committed to respecting your privacy. External users (this excludes users who are on the University network or University computers such as students, faculty and staff) can visit official OU Web sites without revealing any personal information. Should you choose to provide us with any personal information, it will only be used by The University of Oklahoma to conduct official University business, and personal information obtained through the University’s web sites will not be disseminated to any unaffiliated third party, except as required by law.

## Information Gathering

We use IP addresses (the Internet address of your computer) to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer our Web site. For example, we employ statistical software to identify that parts of our Web site are most heavily used and which portion of our audience comes from within the OU network. But, we do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable.

Like many other Web sites, portions of The University of Oklahoma’s Web site may use messages given by Web browsers to Web servers, commonly known as cookies, which can be used to provide You with tailored information from a web site. A cookie is an element of data that a web site can send to Your browser, which may then be stored on Your computer system. This element of data is a piece of text, not a program. The Site can only access the information from a cookie sent by the Web site. We cannot access other cookies sent by other web sites or the information contained there in. Additionally, We cannot learn Your email address or any other information about You through the use of a cookie. The only way the University would learn such information is if You specifically submit that information.

Overall, the use of cookies helps to give You a customized experience at the Web site. Through the use of cookies, the University will know what’s working and what’s not. That information is then used to keep our Web site fresh and relevant to You the user. Cookies also allow the personalization of any online services the University or its affiliates may provide to You.

You may decline to accept cookies sent by the Web site by selecting an option on Your browser to reject cookies. Other sites linked to the Web site may also send cookies; however the University does not control such activities. If You decline a cookie, You may not be viewing the Website in a way in which it was designed to optimally be presented.

## Security

All official OU Web servers have appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures in place to safeguard and secure all information we collect online. Furthermore, we use encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information.

## Third Party Hosting

The University may contract with one or more third parties to maintainand host the Web site(s). Therefore, any information You submit, including personal information, may be placed and stored on a computer server maintained by this third party. Your use of the Web site and any provision of personal information You submit to the Web site constitutes Your acknowledgement that such information or content could pass through and may be stored in servers outside our control. You agree that the University has no liability or responsibility for any such pass through or storage of same.

## Third Party Sites

Sites within the OU Web may link to external sites outside of the OUdomain as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave he OU Web site. The University of Oklahoma is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites, and does not make any representations about them.

## Copyright

Sites within the OU Web may link to external sites outside of the OU domain as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the OU Web site. The University of Oklahoma is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites, and does not make any representations about them.

## Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action

The University of Oklahoma in compliance with all applicable Federal and State laws and regulations does not discriminate on the basis of race, color, national origin, sex, age, religion, disability, political affiliation, or status as a veteran in any of its policies, practices, or procedures. This includes but is not limited to admission, employment, financial aid, and educational services.

## FERPA

The University of Oklahoma complies with all aspects of Public-Law 93-380, the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act. [Please click here for information on this privacy act.](http://admissions.ou.edu/ferpa.htm)

## Effective Dates and Changes

This Privacy Policy is effective as of September, 2007. The University reserves the right to modify the terms of this policy at any time and in its sole discretion, by posting a change notice to this page. Your continued use of the Web site following our posting of a change notice will constitute binding acceptance of those changes and this Privacy Policy.
